# **David Maxey**

Puyallup, Washington, United States



dpmaxey@gmail.com



2538207367



linkedin.com/in/davethetech

# Summary

Helping people is a passion and therefore I never work a day in my life. I strive to help those around me succeed, no matter the distance it takes. I take pride in my work, as it is an art of itself and those who experience it will remember it.

I have been working with technology for half my life and am consistently learning new skills and trades everyday. Working on getting certifications and building long lasting business relationships.

Providing Technology and Web Solutions through my small business Spark PC in the Greater Puget Sound area.

I am also in a partnership with Cranial Designs, providing marketing materials and graphics.

Managing and doing much more than just business, he's typically with his family, hanging with good friends, gaming and watching YouTube.

# **Experience**

#### SPHRIPE Business Owner

Spark PC

Oct 2009 - Present (11 years 4 months +)

I'm the owner of a small-business providing technology and web solutions.

### Laser Operator

**Torklift Central** 

Jun 2020 - Dec 2020 (7 months)

#### 🔝 Information Technology Business Consultant

Tech Mafia

Oct 2019 - May 2020 (8 months)

#### Computer Numerical Control Programmer

Solid Surface Solutions

Jun 2019 - Oct 2019 (5 months)



#### **Uber Partner**

Uber

Mar 2019 - Oct 2019 (8 months)

I help people get to where they need to go, safely and provide the best customer service within the vehicle. Setting the standard for the top-tier drivers.



### Help Desk Coordinator

Your Business Solutions, Inc.

Jan 2019 - Feb 2019 (2 months)

Coordinate Help Desk ticket board, Automated Call Distribution system, e-mails/follow ups, calls, SMS, other notifications, create reports, assign tickets to proper support techs, update KB articles, update client configuration files, maintain customer service quality and assist with service ticket scheduling and technical support throughout Tier 1 - Tier 3 and Dispatch. Project management, e-mail migrations from IMAP/Google Apps/Network Solutions/Etc to Office 365. Active Directory intermediate maintenance, hardware/software diagnostics, remote control software, network AV deployments, Web work such as modifying pages, adding content, diagnosing issues with WordPress and other CMS and sites. E-mail marketing material such as e-mail signature creation. VoIP desk phone support, Experience working with Azure, Auto Desk CAD, Adobe DC, Office 365, Intermedia Exchange server, HR hiring/ firing assistance. Cellphone e-mail setups and support (iPhone / Android). Virtual Machine intermediate experience. Backup devices and software maintenance and monitoring. Xerox, HP, Brother, Ricoh/ Savors printer copier device maintenance and support.



### 🔼 Help Desk Coordinator

Your Business Solutions, Inc.

Jan 2018 - Feb 2019 (1 year 2 months)

Coordinate Help Desk ticket board, Automated Call Distribution system, e-mails/follow ups, calls, SMS, other notifications, create reports, assign tickets to proper support techs, update KB articles, update client configuration files, maintain customer service quality and assist with service ticket scheduling and technical support throughout Tier 1 - Tier 3 and Dispatch. Project management, e-mail migrations from IMAP/Google Apps/Network Solutions/Etc to Office 365. Active Directory intermediate maintenance, hardware/software diagnostics, remote control software, network AV deployments, Web work such as modifying pages, adding content, diagnosing issues with WordPress and other CMS and sites. E-mail marketing material such as e-mail signature creation. VoIP desk phone support, Experience working with Azure, Auto Desk CAD, Adobe DC, Office 365, Intermedia Exchange server, HR hiring/ firing assistance. Cellphone e-mail setups and support (iPhone / Android). Virtual Machine intermediate experience. Backup devices and software maintenance and monitoring. Xerox, HP, Brother, Ricoh/ Savors printer copier device maintenance and support.



#### 🔼 Senior Helpdesk Technician

Your Business Solutions, Inc. Jan 2018 - Jan 2019 (1 year 1 month)



#### IT Specialist / Marketing Manager

PC Fix

Nov 2014 - 2017 (3 years 2 months)

I wear multiple hats. Fixing computers is just the beginning of my responsibilities. I help the company by bringing good classic wholesome and personable customer service. Consisten attention to detail, organization, and management is key to providing our customers with the greatest PC repair shop experience there is possible. Going the extra-mile is just a bonus that our customers receive when we work with you. Technical skills required range from repairing an LCD hinge without ordering extra parts when not necessary, laptop screen replacements and other repairs completed within the hour when part is available. Viruses, rootkits, adware, malware, junkware, ransomware, popups, performance issues, freezing, slowness, and all of the above are also a handful of the issues taken care at the shop. Consultations for upgrades, performance assessments, diagnostics, and much more. We also have onsite, remote tech support, and even provide monthly maintenance contract work for our business

Besides the routine benchwork that I provide for my neighborhood's customers, I also provide web design and content management services to our company in order to provide our customers with the best available information they need before contacting us. We run a monthly blog that provides our customers with great information regarding technology, security, and data privacy. Check it out at www.getpcfix.com/blog/

#### Client Services Remote Service Technician

Support.com

May 2014 - Sep 2014 (5 months)

Actively listen to customer needs and offer appropriate education of products and services to prevent churn.Respond real time to customer Inbound questions and problems.Make outbound calls to touch base with new customers, determine if satisfied or need help, and ensure the customer is satisfied with their new installation. Utilize resources to up-sell and explain competitive edge. Effective use of persuasive techniques to overcome objections. Educate customers in the use of installed products, service offerings, billing, charges, and product features. Resolve customer complaints and situations calmly and courteously. Troubleshoot and resolve service and technical problems using remote control tools with PC/MAC and tablet. Troubleshoot and resolve issues when the customer is using a smartphone app. Meets retention, sales and customer service performance metrics. Explain and instruct the customer on the value and operation of the product and service. Retain customers at high risk for churn.



#### LRC Assistant / Web Design Tutor

**Career Education Corporation** 

Jan 2014 - May 2014 (5 months)

I work as a Learning Resource Center assistant and as a tutor helping students with their Web Design & Development homework, projects, and finals within International Academy of Design & Technology of Seattle. Also worked here when they switched names to their sister college Sanford-Brown College of Seattle



#### Sales Specialist

Sell Phone Store

Jul 2013 - Sep 2013 (3 months)

Buy, sell, give estimates of used & new cellphones, strike deals, help customers with needs, unlock GSM network cellphones, jailbreak iOS devices, iPhone repair, etc

## Condition Report Writer

Manheim

Oct 2012 - Jan 2013 (4 months)

Inspect vehicles using the governed Manheim Insight Auto Grade / NAAA standards.

#### Part-Time Lot Driver

Manheim

Sep 2012 - Oct 2012 (2 months)

Drive cars for auctions, spot cars in proper locations.

### Field Service Engineer

IST - Installation & Service Technologies, Inc.

Nov 2011 - Aug 2012 (10 months)

Install, maintain, and upgrade point of sale technologies for the restaurant and retail industries. (i.e.:

McD, BK, Taco Bell, Subway, Sonics, Panara Bread, Jack in the Box, etc...)

Drive-thru systems, wireless headset systems, and others such as digital menu board systems.

# CAD Engineer

**Advanced Broadcast Solutions** 

Feb 2008 - Jun 2008 (5 months)

Created detailed block diagrams using AutoCAD2002 from server rack audio/video/data equipment manuals for the design director to implement into the project.

# PC Salesman / Technician

PC Club

Jun 2007 - Sep 2007 (4 months)

Sold computers to customers. Point of Sale system, inventory at the end of the month, answered phone calls, repaired computers, support customers. \$9.00/hr

# Laborer

Leftwich Communications LLC

Jun 2006 - Jul 2006 (2 months)

Helped collect old coax cables from telephone pole lines, also had to control cables near the road-sides, after all cable is down we load it up and haul it to a recycle center. (Temporary)

#### **Education**

# International Academy of Design and Technology-Seattle

Bachelor of Applied Science (BASc), Web Page, Digital/Multimedia and Information

Resources Design

2013 - 2014

President's List Award for Term 1311

President of Student Government Term 1311

Vice-President of Student Government Term 1312

# Green River College

Certification, Webmaster

# Bethel High School

High School Diploma, Computers & Business 2003 - 2006

Mount Tahoma High School

# **Licenses & Certifications**

Certified Webmaster - Green River Community College GES308

### **Skills**

Web Design • Troubleshooting • Technical Support • Small Business Support • WordPress • SEO • Networking • CSS • Web Development • Windows